Hi, I'm george and I'm a program manager in the soaking platform team of the core us
...microsoft urban an are going to present
use be accessories and related...buses team added windows
This talk is really about enabling you to build apps that can connect with
hardware from the past like a thirty-year-old natural gas meter that might connect to an old rs
...connector like this or prototype new hardware like a
temperature sensor that's connected to an...know like this.
How cool would it be if you could write one app that
works on a phone that sports use be accessories desktop or
laptop?
As well as an embedded system like min aboard max for...reply vtwo at
the heart of all of this is windows ten including support for use
be accessories as well as the serial device communication
protocol in our new universal windows app platform.
That's what we're going to cover in this talk.
Windows ten ads.
Usb accessory support yet now you can connect plain old accessories like this
...flash drive to a phone running windows mobile
it also adds a new universal windows
...name space for serial device communication prevalent
and old hardware like rs to the
...as well as future devices not even prototype get both items
...accessories and the serial investments are direct result
of acting on customer feedback from the maker community as well as many
app developers and accessory developers together these
two enable you to build apps that connect with both hardware from the past
...the present perhaps even the future all challenge the audience to create advice
the bridges the...
Once hardware catches up you should be able to physically
can act windows ten phone using usb types see to
...thirty-year-old natural gas meter not exactly a time machine but kind of.
...basically revolves around these two topics.
I'm going to cover usb accessories for both typical inventor specific
accessories and app development for them and arbenz going-to go over the
serial communications name space.
Let's start with usb accessories.
Windows ten mobile skew adds support for use
...connected peripherals...new phones and tablets by use speedo role support
...role basically means...device can act as a peripheral aura
host and dynamically switch between the two of them are teams been working with...
partners on the sport...a new wave of windows ten devices will support
...accessories when windows ten launches as developers you can build
physically connected accessories using open industry standards without per unit
royalties or special discovery protocol unlike other platforms.
Leveraging the our of our windows universal...platform to understand usb
accessories let's first look at the types of accessories that we target.
There's basically two types of accessories and focused on enabling first.
There's typical accessories people just use every day like a flash drive.
Second
there's a set of developers to develop unique functionality think of a smart cover for
a phone call these vendor specific accessories because
the typically require an avp from the accessory provider.
Let's first start with typical accessories.
So, this slide basically covers the types of typical
...that the mobile skew supports natively.
Typical accessories have api and built-in device drivers in the os that
standardize commands and responses across vendors,
for example, flash drives your microphones from different
...or credit card reader from manufacture a and manufacture
be the key is the you can develop one app that works regardless of those things.
Secondarily many of these accessory types support.
Like browsing files or recording audio also include built-in user experiences
in the windows mobile platform.
So, this slide contains a list of the
...natively support on mobile sq which explicitly support app development.
And, you can see the namespaces that you can use to accessible.
It's also worth understanding there's a set of natively supported
accessories like for productivity scenarios like keyboards
and mice network adapters aren't directly of
use to app developers well seeing is believing let's take a
look at the demo so I'd like to demonstrate just using a...flash drive like
this one here on a handset running windows mobile windows ten mobile.
I'm getting ready to go on a business trip to europe I
...catch up on some videos from the
...have developer conference that I messed so I can copy the mp for
...this used flash drive.
So, I can watch them while...in-flight this is a development handset that supports use
...accessories by do rules support.
For levi copy the files on to this flash drive so that while
...I can watch them let's see can bring up the file
explorer.
You can see some of the files there on
the attach card so let's catch up on some...don boxes keynote from one hack.
Microsoft...
So, now I can binge watch all
these videos while I'm on my plane.
And, even and even better yet.
I can have more videos
the form natively supports in storage.
Next forget vendors specific accessories those the ones that are
...typically require...from the
folks who developed the accessory examples include
smart covers fitness devices robot's smart toys in the like.
The app commands or commonly unique and not
standardized across different hardware manufacturers and the
...do not often fit into well-defined class let's look an example.
So, I'd like to demo nor do we know on esp handset.
Is a very simple future use
...accessory on...development handset that sports use...role?
Built with the...or do we know prototyping platform?
May folks used to make new accessories and thanks here's a
super simple app that reads data from a temperature sensor and
whites data to the leads on the board you can see that
I'm controlling the different leads by just flicking these toggle is here.
All the hardware that
I'm showing cost roughly forty dollars and can be ordered from amazon and
...that I'm showing as well as the sample source code
for the microcode for the...now and the wiring diagram we plan to publishing early june?
Now this is just a simple example of something you can easily prototype
using art window and the support.
In windows...
You can also do way more advance things, for example, from...quality
folks are actually working on a way to build a voltage meter using something like this to
actually measure the quality of the usb...functionality on...handsets.
what does windows offer for developing apps for
vendor specific accessories?
So, windows ten includes hid cereal and use be api and
...built into the windows ten mobile...
These api as part of the when universal windows app platform...can use them on
Or vented systems or even phones leveraging your
prior familiarity for developing for them on these new form factors like
phone's embedded systems.
In the language of your choice so these namespaces and these sdk
samples or providing it build and they also work
on handsets sport use below rule like this...development handset.
Here's an important point to understand about developing accessories.
For...specific accessories it super important to get make sure that your
accessory installs the right driver so that are api...can accesses.
Your accessory can use these methods there's a set of compatible
ideas and will provide more in the resources layer about how your device
can report itself so that these drivers will just install?
It's important to recognize that are mobile skew does not support
installation vendor...like from windows update
...basically more like a phone instead of a pc.
The usb serial driver that we include windows ten in particular
addresses key customer feedback on improving reliability and installing and
...compatible ideas on boards like...windows
that lots of people have given us some very good feedback on all three these...cover.
Future accessories and hardware pretty well all three
...cover future accessories and hardware pretty well.
There's one important scenario for past hardware I'd like to challenge the audience to address.
Customers need access hardware like thirty-year-old natural gas meters using with rs
two-thirty to connectors like this and they typically use
...speed rs two-thirty to adaptor cable to do so.
I'd like to challenge the audience.
To build one of these cables that actually reports the compatible ideas that are
built-in use research dot...supports natively the first company do
...get recognition on our api documentation
as well as the web page this videos hosted on.
So, how can you start developing apps for use be accessories today?
It's pretty simple you probably already have most of the stuff that you need...
start with just developing universal app on a desktop or laptop...has use before.
Just make sure that the ux
...properly on different form factors like a handset.
And, then finally once dual handset.
One-third available get...capable mobile device test your app with accessories.
So, how can you do that last part find dual capable device?
It's actually very good question.
Now especially before these devices...the market you need a new phone or tablet
your manufacturer says supports usb do role.
If you're buying a new one look for a device that
your manufacturer says supports...role.
If you already have a device the windows ten user experience one vacated like the
screenshot here from this are usb settings page tells us the device supports use
...connections to devices like keyboards in mice.
Well, that's the usb accessories part of our talk next I'd like
to introduce armand who's going to present the windows dot devices
that serial communication name space armand thanks george.
Hi, my name's marvin I'm a software engineer I work with georgian the
buses steam in the operating systems group and
...going to talk about serial communication using
...so george give you a good introduction about how now we have enabled us
be accessories to work with...tour of windows devices like
phone's tablets and embedded devices unload focus on
a specific aspect of which namely how do you talk to us be serial devices are
...devices in general using our new when
...name space that we've introduced in windows step.
So, let's start with an overview
of in windows eight-point one if you recall we introduced the notion
of the protocol level access.
What protocol level access implies is you can use standard protocols like
...usb bluetooth, bluetooth...to a device
using windows runtime this enables a growing community
...hardware developers to write apps for their either custom devices
are well-known devices using technologies that are simple and
easy-to-use?
To add to that long list of protocol aps in windows
...we add serial communication to the list and it's a little bit ironic
...serial communication predates some of these protocols but hey better late than
never.
And, this portion of the
...focuses on the nuances and the intricacies of the windows
serial communication api that the supported in windows step.
So, let's go back a little bit and understand why did we decide to add
...to the protocol level aps.
We recognize that there's a really strong interest in
the developer community as well as in the retail world to communicate with
serial devices serial devices aren't going away there
a lot of them you can see from the little r do we node to commercial and,
enterprise level gas meters and things like that
serial communications are part of forward and it's really more
important nowadays when you talk about embedded systems where have they have
...controller's you arts and stuff like that on them that
serial communication is still part of the...technology space.
Moreover there is an existing ecosystem of when
thirty-two apps that you can use to talk to...devices everybody knows that you
know, you can use you have can write a wintry to app that can open
...tending data and reading data from your seo devices.
And, especially with the advent of the infinite of things...embedded systems more and
more of these devices are there in the marketplace so with the promise of windows
...and the universal windows app it makes perfect sense to bring
...into the with...forward so this slide summarizes the new
experiences with serial communication that are there in windows step.
...as with all other protocol api is
there's a built-in device discovery model which allows you to
discover access and instantiate the your seo devices
there's of course the new windows runtime api with simplifies communication with
...device?
the final point which is that it works with windows universal apps
which means you can write take once and deployed everywhere.
you can see you can you can see that you don't have to do anything specific
for making your app work on full
...order tablet or desktop or on...device.
So, let's before we go into the depth of the
...be good to sort of set some prerequisites about what
would be useful for you...a absorb the content of the stock.
First of all it's important to know a little bit about how serial communication works and,
I'm a lot of the audience who's interested in writing when
...apps for cereal are probably familiar with the
...thirty-two programming interface it's probably good to know about that there's also the
docked net...programming interface so familiarity with
those would help in absorbing the content of how...works with
...as well and of course since we're in the realm of the windows runtime
brushing up or being familiar with some concepts which are unique to the
windows runtime like a single operations device operations is also useful.
So, let's look at the architecture of how this is all laid out
in windows so you have your windows a universal store
universal windows app right at the top of this layer cake this
uses the windows dot devices dot serial communication api which is
the runtime component and these together run in the
app container process which is where all of windows universal apps run.
The runtime component uses the native
serial layer and by that I mean just a bunch of...there's
an existing I'll interface for cereal and we just reuse that.
And, that is also a device broker component the
aft communicate with the device below...device broker sits on the side and,
...go into a little bit of detail into what exactly the device access broker does so the device
access broker is an actually and os component whose role it is to do
some basic bookkeeping and gate keeping for device access aps.
In the to drop parallels with the...thirty-two or the...
network where there was no real gate keeping like if you were able to discover
the serial device you were able to open a handle do it and start sending a
...however,
however, with windows apps we uphold certain app container principals and
promises and user promises and hence the device access broker access the
mediator the gatekeeper before we allow access using these opaque
types.
So, with that ...set let's go and look at
the demo about how exactly all these things are laid out all right what
...going to demo here is a simple windows universal
app that has been developed in visual studio that uses the windows
serial communication aps and this app will work with a
are...development board and
...who node to be precise which is right here the setup is really simple
we've wired...for...
And, a temperature sensor to this are... board and
it's connected via usb to the mobile handset.
So, let's see what exactly does so I'm going to launch the app.
And, it's just a simple app which has controls for a bunch of a
...as well as getting the temperature the first thing I'm going to do is actually connect.
The device and you can see that it shows here the devices
been connected and then I'm going to start by targeting each of these leads
...I toggle and...you'll notice that the corresponding and
...on the board has just let up all right so let's see let's start by targeting some
...the board so, I'm...of press these ellie b buttons and you can see
that they alternatively go on and off.
And, I'm going to turn them on again one by one so on so forth and
there's a little temperature button here which I'm going to which because there's a temperature center that's wired up to the...do we know
...I'm just going to press this and it's going to show you the current temperature so you can see that
it's reading twenty-two the thirty-one and then it keeps varying so I'm just
going to maybe this press this lady and see if I can get it to heat up a little bit
and then see if I compressed...temperature and see so you can see the very slightly
so it's fairly straightforward ...is reading and writing to the
...know report now
...let's see if we can now the same app let's see if
...make it work on a laptop that I have connected here so I'm going to unplugged this
...usb cable...of plug it into my laptop.
So, the same happen we're now launch from my laptop and you'll see that it works
exactly the same way as we saw on the mobile handset.
Someone...connect to the device
...toggle the leads back on there you see.
On and off on and off so on and the temperature
sensor works as well all right so that was a mobile
handset a desktop let's add an embedded system into the mix.
So, I'm going to move.
We are doing well I'm going to connected to a.
...board...we have here which is also running
a version of windows and.
You'll see the same thing happening and now we're going to launch the same
avp from.
A minnow board on a maynard were back to just running a version of windows and
you'll see and we've hooked up the are do we know to the middle board...going to now launched the app.
Then I'm going to start by...the leads back on and off again.
there you go so you can see the our of windows universal apps
know-how you can write your app
once deployed on a variety of systems form factors
running windows and get the same experience
using the new windows runtime aps all right now that you saw the
cool demo let's go into delve a little bit into the nitty-gritty of what it took
toget this all working the way we structure the remainder of this
talk is to provide a walk through of what it actually takes to build a
i-device app for a serial device.
So, the advantage of this step-by-step process will become really apparent because
...a few key pieces that you need to get
...in order to successfully communicate with your device.
So, there are four main step that most apps will tend to get to
the follow to get started
and this is pretty much universal across most device
apps that you will encounter in the windows runtime first of all
do you need to declare what is called the capability so the capability declaration
is a means to express the in...of what the app
will use it could be some really high-level construct like internet or
...location but since
we're actually focusing on device specific stuff what we're going to talk about
what we're going to use is device capabilities the
next step is to find the devices your...interested in
and actually instantiated which is where device discovery comes in once you
figure out the device to of the particular device or devices that you're
interested in talking to then you can instantiate the device
and of course you can start communicating with the device and finally
when we're done we of course cleanup so let's look
at each of these steps in a bit more detail the first one is like we mention
...declaration the capability declaration resides
in the aspects manifest there is a package start affects manifest file
that's generated with every windows universal
app solution and inside that you have to declare a device
capability for...communication the top-level device capability
is just a full name which is...communication within that there are two sub
...firstly it's the device
id and the second one is the function type?
So, for...devices that are two types of device
id you can use one is a device idea of any which
implies you're interested in finding any and all...devices
alternately you could specify...device id.
With the usb vid and afraid for a usb serial device like
...just demos and this is this pretty much the usb
...and then in the function type capability
declaration you need to declare
...particular function on the...you're interested in, for example,
if you had a multi function device you would be interested in talking to the
serial part of it hence the name serial port is what
you would declare in the function type declaration.
All right so we have the device properties let's see how they look
like in the app x manifest and this is simply an example of a
package or affects manifest file in visual studio and towards the bottom you can see
...device capability declaration which shows the
serial communication top-level
namespaces well as the individual device id decorations.
And, here
...of the same affects manifest the first one shows you how to
declare device idea of any kind of function type of serial port
in the second one is uses the usb
...and...followed by the function type of the device which is still
...so that's straightforward enough so once you have the capability
declaration windows and the app platform knows that you intend to talk to
...devices maybe a...one
...all of them so then we move on to device discovery.
So, for...devices the
way windows has traditionally treated them is by the abstraction known as a comp
work a comp...is essentially
...identifier for a serial device...it's plugged into the system and
its assigned in sequential order
by it component within the os known as the class installer or the
sports class installer which gets handed just during when the devices installed...you plug it
...and the comp port also gets assigned a symbolic link which
apps can use to open a handle to it now there are some problems with
this approach obviously a com poured...telling us a whole lot about the device
it's just abstract out any detailed description or particular
types of devices all you really knows about hey I have some serial device which is plugged
...one comp to work on three.
And, of course when you talk when you want to do real discovery since the
com pork number can vary across systems where it's plugged
...you really can't rely on the device getting assign the same com
...number across systems which means you
can't really identify the device in the same way across-the-board.
So, to alleviate all these problems and to fit in with the windows runtime
model there is a much more augmented device discovery pattern that we use
...definition of when in windows runtime of a serial devices
...expanded to more than a com
...it can be some kind of device identifier,
for example, if you have a usb serial device you can specified using if,
you know, it's vendor...and product id you-can discovered using back or if the serial device
...bridge that it was using to connect the pc maybe it's the
vent righty the product idea of the bridgeif, for example,
you had a way to display the friendly name of the device or tag some
more descriptive name like a print three-d printer or are doing so
on then you can discover the device using that friendly name assuming...a set appropriately?
With this augmented discovery model you will discover that finding device
...devices is now
piece of cake and you don't and it can be it can be deterministic.
how do you go about actually discovering the device the first thing we need is a selector a
selector is just a formatted string using a syntax which we call a
...or advanced query syntax?
This is a pretty standard mechanism that we use for all devices
enumeration ...within windows fortunately we have a couple of static
device selectors that we've built into the serial communication name space and there are three
device selectors which are just outlined here the first one without any parameters
...devices on the system or you can decide to
...device selector with a string which is a
...name or friendly name or device lecture with the usb varied?
And, then once you have this device selector returns back in a us you-can fast
aac us to a device enumeration aps that are built into windows in the devices
dot enumeration name space which is to find all...
seeing or the create water methods and...give you back a list of all devices
that...specifically gives you back a list of device information objects and
then finally you can walk through the list of device enumeration objects are find the one
you're interested in and actually open the device which in when
...is by calling from id facing and from id asynchronous
the covers essentially just open to handle to the device and gives you back an object that you can
start...using in your app?
And, of course you can use that percent...to the devices.
So, let's look at how it looks encode we'd like we just went through you
have a selector in this case we're using a selector which uses the us beaverton
...there's another example for selector which uses the friendly name which.
Can also become one if that's what it shows up as and then we call
...to find all the devices on the system and
then to instantiate the device we call from id a...which gives you
backan actual serial device object that you could use
quick word here you need to worry about the case
when the devices...and we go into a little bit of detail a little later in the
...all right so when you call from id a...what really happens?
We have a bunch of checks that we do before we
...access to the device so when you call from id
...it means windows is going through those checks and giving you
handle that you can now send
io over but before that handles given back we have to do a bunch of runtime
checks of course we check that you have declared the right capability declaration
...app...manifests which if you recall was the
intend to talk to a particular device then we
also check whether there's any os policy restrictions in place to let you talk to
...particular serial device we also look for exclusivity
...devices our...nature so if one app has it open
...another apple get access tonight so we
...for exclusivity and finally there's this notion of consent
our dynamic access.
quick word and consent because this has evolved from windows eight-point
...to windows stent...the requirement for
...consent inwindows stent specifically there is no longer a at
...a pop-up that shows up that is presented to the user before
...actually grant access to the device instead for
cereal and haired...on most device protocol api is consent
is granted automatically and the user can actually change that by going to
the bc settings page under privacy and dynamically revoke or
...access to the app before giving access to the device.
Now as a result of any of these steps
if it somehow discovered that the device
...cannot be open for any of these
reasons what you will get back is a nulls here and device objects so what do you do
then so if you encounter a situation whereby from id a synched gave back
...object then you can optional
...called these other device access information aps to figure out
a more detail status as to why
...not allowed to open a...to the devices.
Again,
this is an awful step it's not a must do but if you were to file if you
wanted more information on what exactly happened here is not here's the way to do it.
All right so now we've gone from capability declaration we've
talked about discovery and instantiation let's talk about communication.
So, communication exact has three steps essentially you
have basic configuration you want to configure the serial device which if you're familiar with
...devices things like baud rate parity stop bits handshakes
etc and then reading and writing from the device and we
over-loaded existing concepts in the windows runtime by which are input
stream's output stream's data...and data writers.
So, let's look at the communications
so the first step likely talked about was configuration in this case
here we have a bunch of configuration parameters like baud rate stop
bits and parity that you'd know ahead of time that the device uses.
And, then.
Writing and reading so the first part is writing so if you wanted to write the device
...would use the output stream property that's there in the serial device object
and fill in the data that you create from this output stream
with whatever in this case I'm just showing you a way to write hello over a
...pork and then you can call load a sink on it and the
send the data on that stream and you can check back to see how many...were written.
Similarly reading from the...
is using input streams so you would create a new data reader you would
specify how many bites you want to read from the data reader and then you would
...load a...on it and in this case I'm just reading the
same string back so if you if this was like hooked up in
a loop back configuration you would just see hello being transferred across the wire
so that's really what that is to reading and writing so it's fairly straightforward ...a few
other a events so on which we've left to as an exercise for the reader.
Finally we should also...remember to clean-up after we're done doing any kind
...with the device so the first thing the app must do is to
close the serial device which in underneath the covers essentially ends up closing the
handle device so that other apps or
...other entities in the system can start using
that device again and...important nuance that
you we should remember for close is to be aware of language specific
usage is a about how to closer device.
And, we look at that again here so closing the device and cplus-plus looks
...district delete whereas in csharp you actually have to
call dispose on the serial device object.
Another point that is important to also keep in mind is app suspension...resume
of windows apps windows universal apps are subject to suspension
and resumption so if they were not in use they can be move
to the background and brought back into the for...as the user switches back and forth.
So, what should you do in your app when it's suspended if
...suspended first of all must register for the suspension notification
and in the notification you must close the serial device because it'll get hot invalid and
...no longer be valid it'snot send any new I'll and,
when the app gets resumed it must reopen the device all over again
and start from scratch well not really start from scratch but at least you can
...the device information object regard and reopen the...to it?
So, with that all said let's go back and look at
what it took to write the app that we demos on the...and
...walk you through each of these steps that we talked about in the slides and see how
the look in code.
All right so let's look at each of the steps that we talked about and
slide encode and see how this all plays out so likely mentioned the first step
...is the same...app code that we were using to talk to the are doing
...demo earlier so all of this is will be available in early juneand,
you can download this code...the app code as well as a sketch for the are doing and see how
this all works together so.
Here's the first step images connecting to the device finding and connecting to the device likely
mentioned the we use a selector and the selector this time
is we specify the are doing ovarian the fit.
The selector returns
formatted string in the aac us format we pass that to find all
...and that gives you a collection
...device information collection objects.
Since in this case is a pretty simple ad there's just one...do we know connected if you
do have a single that we've if there's account is greater than zero we just.
Open the first one in the collection.
And, once you open from id a sinking of
that succeeds that means you were successfully able to open...the device and
you got a non-null serial device object.
Then you can go ahead and configured the serial device in this case we set
a bunch of properties on it which is the baud rate parity stop...
And, the devices ready to be a communicated with so now you can send some
bio to it so let's talk look at reeds and...we look at
rights first in this case let's look at particularly how the leads work
...and off so we have a function here which is the right
...on command function so it's a pretty straightforward protocol.
We create a new data writer using the output stream on the
serial device object and we write a string which is
...the on followed by the...numbers...for this would look like
...on three and the sketch would the firmware on
it would automatically goggle set that particular been to high
...what happens at the device level so I have...data writer
...fillet in with the string and then I call stories
...clinic and then this goes ahead across
the stream and then using the aps...tend...the same command down to the device.
We have an...
of parallel to this which is exactly the same except we just call it
...off along with the...number.
So, that was writing and reading follows a similar pattern reading was when we looked
at that temperature and how we got the temperature we have
an output stream here?
And, the first thing we have to do actually in this particular sketch we have
actually send the string...down to the device before you can actually
read from it so this is what it actually shows you actually send the string
called damp and then we ve back from the device.
And, reading like we just talked about earlier is setting up an input stream with
...and data reader instantiating it reading seven bites from it which
is that's what the protocol returns and then displaying what was the number of bytes
...as a specs which is what the temperature is about and that's really all there is to it
we talked about finding the device discovering it opening handle do
...configuring if writing through it and reading from
it which is really all field communications all about
all right so we looked at the demo we looked at how it looks encode.
Let's talk about the little bit about additional features that are there is part
of this api in particular we want to talk a little bit about background...
Because that's also a...builds bits built into the windows runtime.
Apps can do long-running operation using background
tasks you can use a bunch of triggers that are well-defined triggers at
that part of the system like the system event trigger the control channel take...the device used
trigger you can use any of these trigger...trigger background tasks that you can run and
...device importer note here is that tasks are
not throttle like other system background tasks that is there is no cpu time-code
...but the caveat is that it may run with
reduce priority to keep the foreground apps responsive and
...note here is that this actually
...across all device protocol aps linkedin usb and
...of course so, you can now start using bagged you can
...use background tasks without actually getting throttled.
Debugging of course there's debugging built-in into the aps...any issues you can
actually do wb tracing for the communication
...dls as well as a device broker that are details
on msdn page regarding this.
And, here a few related sessions that are relevant as far as the
stock is concerned which you might want to take a look at or look at their recordings
for so I'd like to recap and leave you with a few resources.
First for developing apps for typical accessories
...mobile skew just remember these are accessories that just work
with the os we have the following namespaces for them.
For audio devices removable
storage and files point of service so check out the msdn page and
...namespaces documentation as well as the samples for this.
Next for...specific accessories this
is the namespaces head...the new serial communications
...just walked...as well as windows dot devices...usb.
And, all...samples for these are also.
Universal windows app platform samples
work on all the different platforms and form factors that we just showed you.
Just one leave you with the simple called action.
So, if you're developing usb accessories just start out
involving universal windows app on a desktop with us before.
Make sure that the ux without properly on
a mobile phone.
And, then once available...
rule cable handset start testing your accessory with your app also
...make sure that your accessory declares the right hardware id so
...work with our in the os box drivers on the mobile skew
because remember or mobile skews more like a phone...a pc.
And, lastly.
Your feedback is super important to us
with truthfully we wouldn't have done any of this work without your feedback kind of
where all starts so if we happen to be missing anything please feel free to
e-mail feedback to
...api fbi microsoft-dot-com
so we can stay on top of what else matters you folks so that
maybe next year build we can talk about that thank you so much thanks.